{"1": {"question": "What genre is Frühlingstraum?", "correct": "A Romantic Lied (German art song)", "incorrect": ["An English art song", "A romantic art song", "Jazz", "Rock"]}, "2": {"question": "What are the main keys used in Frühlingstraum?", "correct": "F Major and F Minor", "incorrect": ["E Major and E minor", "G Major, G minor and D minor", "C Major and G minor", "F Major and C Major"]}, "3": {"question": "Why was Frühlingstraum transposed from A major and A minor to F Major and F Minor?", "correct": "To suit a lower voice. ", "incorrect": ["To make it easier to play.", "Because Schubert felt like it.", "Because no-one liked the key of the song.", "Because Schubert got sick of the original key."]}, "4": {"question": "What does Frühlingstraum mean?", "correct": "Spring dream or Dream of Spring", "incorrect": ["Spring Journey", "Blossoming Flowers", "Spring Breeze", "Has no particular translation to English"]}, "5": {"question": "What is the form of Frühlingstraum?", "correct": "A slightly modified version of strophic form.", "incorrect": ["Modified Strophic form", "Through Composed Form", "Binary Form", "Sonata Form"]}, "6": {"question": "What does 'Etwas bewegt' mean?", "correct": "Moving along (similar to Con Moto)", "incorrect": ["Previous Tempo", "Slow and Gentle", "Extremely Fast", "Powerful and Loud"]}, "7": {"question": "What does 'Schnell' mean?", "correct": "Fast", "incorrect": ["Raw Chicken", "Suddenly Play softly", "Moderately Slow", "Gradually increase in volume"]}, "8": {"question": "What does 'Langsam' mean?", "correct": "Slow", "incorrect": ["Very Soft", "Moderately light ", "Play very Smoothly", "Moderately Slow"]}, "9": {"question": "Who wrote the source material that Schubert used for 'Frühlingstraum'?", "correct": "Wilhelm Müller", "incorrect": ["Bach", "George Handel", "Schumann", "William Shakespeare"]}, "10": {"question": "Which other keys are briefly used in Frühlingstraum?", "correct": "C minor, B flat major and E flat minor", "incorrect": ["G minor and A Minor", "Just B Major", "C# Minor and G# major", "C Major, G major and A Major"]}, "11": {"question": "What movement # is Frühlingstraum (within the larger work it is a part of)?", "correct": "11", "incorrect": ["12", "16", "14", "10"]}, "12": {"question": "What larger work is Frühlingstraum from?", "correct": "Winterreise", "incorrect": ["Die schöne Müllerin", "Dichterliebe", "Kindertotenlieder", "Liederkreis, Op. 39"]}, "13": {"question": "What type of work is the larger work that Frühlingstraum is from?", "correct": "Lieder", "incorrect": ["Art song", "Pop", "Blues", "Country Music"]}, "14": {"question": "What does Winterreise mean in English?", "correct": "Winter Journey", "incorrect": ["Winter Nights", "Winter Life", "Cold Winters", "Sad Winter"]}, "15": {"question": "Which Two Stanzas in Frühlingstraum change to 2/4?", "correct": "Stanzas 3 and 6", "incorrect": ["Stanzas 1 and 2", "Stanzas 1 and 4", "Stanzas 2 and 5", "No stanzas have a time signature of 2/4"]}, "16": {"question": "What is a Lied?", "correct": "German art song", "incorrect": ["Trumpian Rhetoric", "Art song in English", "How you stop a dog from running away", "A German folk song for 2 voices"]}, "17": {"question": "What language is Frühlingstraum in?", "correct": "German", "incorrect": ["Dutch", "Latin", "French", "Spanish"]}, "18": {"question": "Which poet has had the most Lieder set to their text?", "correct": "Goethe", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Shakespeare", "Schubert", "Wilhelm Müller"]}, "19": {"question": "When was the Lied developed?", "correct": "Late 18th Century", "incorrect": ["Late 1800s", "Early 18th Century", "Early 1800s", "Last year"]}, "20": {"question": "Where did Schubert live?", "correct": "Vienna, Austria", "incorrect": ["Vienna, Australia", "Salzburg, Austria", "Munich, Germany", "London, UK"]}, "21": {"question": "When was Winterreise composed?", "correct": "1828", "incorrect": ["1868", "1768", "2028", "Trick question, it wasn't composed!"]}, "22": {"question": "Who was the first composer to link multiple Lieder together into a coherent cycle?", "correct": "Beethoven", "incorrect": ["Schubert", "Mozart", "Finzi", "Bach"]}, "23": {"question": "What did the development of a song cycle allow composers to do?", "correct": "Explore larger themes and ideas over a greater span of time and with more dramatic development.", "incorrect": ["Put songs in a certain order", "Sort their songs into smaller parts to make it easier for people to learn", "To show the audience their favourite songs in order"]}, "24": {"question": "What are individual lieder put together into cycles called?", "correct": "Liederkreis", "incorrect": ["Lieder cycle", "Liedergroup", "Song cycle"]}, "25": {"question": "What is the name of Beethoven's first Liederkreis?", "correct": "An die ferne Geliebte, Op. 98", "incorrect": ["He didn't compose any", "Dichterliebe, Op. 48", "Liederkreis, Op. 24"]}, "26": {"question": "What does 'Wie Oben' mean?", "correct": "As above, to play the above tempo", "incorrect": ["Play original tempo", "As above, to play the above dynamics", "Gradually increase in tempo"]}, "27": {"question": "What is 'ligato'?", "correct": "An alternate spelling of legato", "incorrect": ["An incorrect spelling of legato", "It means to play freely", "To come to a sudden stop"]}, "28": {"question": "What does 'legato' mean?", "correct": "Smooth and connected", "incorrect": ["Cooked Chicken legs", "To play loud and strongly", "Decrease in dynamic until it is the same as the piano's"]}, "29": {"question": "What does lied mean?", "correct": "Song in German", "incorrect": ["Tempo ", "The past tense of telling a false statement", "To suddenly increase in dynamic (translated from Italian)", "A strap or chain used to tether a pet while walking them."]}, "30": {"question": "How far do songs with German texts go back?", "correct": "The middle ages", "incorrect": ["World war 1", "The 1800s", "1999", "Approximately 8 metres"]}, "31": {"question": "How many lieder did Schubert compose in his career?", "correct": "Over 600", "incorrect": ["356", "No-one kept track of how many he wrote", "Only 5"]}, "32": {"question": "How old was Schubert when he composed Winterreise?", "correct": "~31 years old", "incorrect": ["16 Years old", "42", "The exact year when Schubert wrote Winterreise is still unknown"]}, "33": {"question": "An important factor in the development of the Romantic Lied was the growing availability and popularity of what?", "correct": "The Piano", "incorrect": ["Uranium", "Manuscript paper", "Voices", "Formal music training"]}, "34": {"question": "When was Schubert alive?", "correct": "1797-1828", "incorrect": ["1787-1828", "1828-1797 BCE", "       1797-1892"]}, "35": {"question": "Which part of Schubert's lifetime was Winterreise composed?", "correct": "Near the end", "incorrect": ["Roughly halfway through", "No one knew, he composed this Liederkreis secretly", "In his teen years"]}, "36": {"question": "What is a lied?", "correct": "A song set to a German Text", "incorrect": ["A song set to English text", "The beginning of a musical section", "A song with two parts"]}, "37": {"question": "Which century did lied gain widepread recognition as a high art form?", "correct": "19th Century", "incorrect": ["2nd April, 1851", "18th Century", "21st Century", "29th Century"]}, "38": {"question": "Who developed the idea that language was the most significant determinant of social cohesion?", "correct": "Johann Gottfried Herder", "incorrect": ["Henry Purcell", "Benjamin Britten", "Ralph Vaugn Williams", "Beethoven"]}, "39": {"question": "German lied were produced in significant numbers for what?", "correct": "Domestic Consumption", "incorrect": ["No particular reason", "To get the German president Interested", "Radio stations"]}, "40": {"question": "What are iambs?", "correct": "Two syllables in unstressed-stressed configuration", "incorrect": ["Meat from a sheep", "Short and sharp staccatos", "A marking to hold a note for its entire value", "Three syllables in unstressed-stressed-unstressed configuration"]}, "41": {"question": "What is an amphibrach?", "correct": "Three syllables in unstressed-stressed-unstressed configuration", "incorrect": ["Two syllables in unstressed-stressed configuration", "Lieder", "A type of animal", "A sea slug", "Three syllables in stressed-unstressed-unstressed configuration"]}, "42": {"question": "How long did Schubert live in the capital of Austria?", "correct": "His whole life", "incorrect": ["For 12 years", "The first half of his life", "He never did", "29 years"]}, "43": {"question": "Schubert's Gretchen am Spinnrade (Gretchen at the Spinning Wheel) Op. 22 D 118 stood out as what?", "correct": "A milestone in the evolution in the genre (lied)", "incorrect": ["One of the worst representations of the lied genre.", "One of the greatest masterpieces of the early Romantic German lied.", "A milestone in the evolution of art song"]}, "44": {"question": "How many bars does the piano introduction at the beginning Frühlingstraum last for?", "correct": "4 Bars", "incorrect": ["12 bars", "8 bars", "6 bars", "32 bars"]}, "45": {"question": "What does 'Singstimme' mean?", "correct": "Voice", "incorrect": ["Time to sing", "Piano", "In a gentle manner"]}, "46": {"question": "What is the main time signature of Frühlingstraum?", "correct": "6/8", "incorrect": ["3/4", "3/8", "9/8"]}, "47": {"question": "When during the piece does the key signature change?", "correct": "It doesn't change at all", "incorrect": ["Development", "Recapitulation", "Section B"]}, "48": {"question": "What is the stanza pattern for Frühlingstraum?", "correct": "abcabc", "incorrect": ["ababc", "aabbabc", "aabbcc"]}, "49": {"question": "Winterreise was widely acknowledged as being what?", "correct": "One of the greatest masterpieces of the early Romantic German lied.", "incorrect": ["One of the first lied to be written", "One of the greatest masterpieces of art song", "Having the longest name for a Liederkreis"]}, "50": {"question": "What was the significance of Beethoven's An die ferne Geliebte (To the distant beloved), Op. 98 (1816)?", "correct": "It was the very first Liederkreis ever put together.", "incorrect": ["It inspired many other composers of the time to give their songs an Op. #", "It was the very first composition to have a German name", "It inspired Finzi to make his first song cycle"]}, "51": {"question": "What is the plural form of lied?", "correct": "Lieder", "incorrect": ["Lieding", "Lieds", "Lieders"]}, "52": {"question": "One important factor in the development of lied was the growth of German as what?", "correct": "A literary language", "incorrect": ["A country", "A nationilty", "A word"]}, "53": {"question": "What are melismas?", "correct": "A group of notes sung to one syllable", "incorrect": ["A group of notes sung with different note values but with the same pitch", "A group of notes sung all slurred", "A group of notes sung staccato"]}, "54": {"question": "What are quatrains?", "correct": "A stanza of four lines", "incorrect": ["Tenor Saxophonists", "A group of four people", "A train with four carriages"]}, "55": {"question": "How many quatrains does Frühingstraum contain?", "correct": "6", "incorrect": ["4", "8", "12"]}}